J. Ignacio Lopez Coll

Calgary, Alberta, Canada | ignacio@lopez-coll.com | https://lopez-coll.com | Open to Relocation Senior Solution Architect Dynamics 365

SUMMARY

As a Dynamics 365 Solution Architect, I've successfully led teams in implementing complex ERP software solutions, and I'm experienced in managing whole projects. My work spans across Europe, North America, and Central America, showcasing my adaptability to various business scenarios. I have a knack for addressing challenging problems and meeting customer needs. Apart from my main duties, I also participate in company initiatives and contribute to the business development in sales activities. Additionally, I founded Plaza 365, a platform to share knowledge on Microsoft business applications, which highlights my dedication to foster learning and collaboration in the industry.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Successfully contributed to over 20 End-to-End implementations (D365FO, AX 2012 & AX 4) across multiple industries.

Key Skills Strategic project planning, stakeholder management, team leadership, cross-

functional collaboration, sales support.

Functional Knowledge All Dynamics 365 Finance & Operations Module.

Dynamics 365 Field Service

Integration Design and Dual Write experience.

Generative AI, Copilot & Open Source AI Solutions. Broad Tech Stack

experience outside Microsoft Ecosystem

Technical Knowledge Python, React, AWS, SQL, Tailwind, HTML, CSS, PHP and X++.

International Capabilities 3 fluent languages (ES, DE and EN).

8 countries implemented. Spanish & Canadian Citizen

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

- 1. MCE (Microsoft Certified Expert) Dynamics 365: Finance and Operations Apps Solution Architect
- 2. **FastTrack for D365** Success by Design
- 3. **Scrum Alliance** Scrum Master
- 4. MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional) Dynamics 365 Finance MB-310
- 5. MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional) Dynamics 365 Supply Chain Management MB-330
- 6. **MCP –** Dynamics 365 Core Finance and Operations MB-300
- 7. **MCP –** Dynamics 365 Financial Management MB6-895
- 8. MCP Dynamics AX 2012 Financials & Dynamics AX Trade and Logistics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

04/2023 - today

Hitachi Solutions Canada Ltd., Calgary, Alberta (Canada) Senior Solution Architect, Dynamics 365

- Collaborate with top executives in steerco meetings, providing valuable insights and contributing to strategic decision-making processes
- Currently dedicated to a large enterprise Field Service implementation across multiple
 Applications with over 250 integration points and 45 applications
- Implement Business Process Management (BPM) strategies for clients, facilitating internal process organization to ensure not only project success but also continuous improvement and organizational effectiveness long after deployment
- Drive internal initiatives to refine implementation methodologies, harnessing AI and innovative technologies to optimize daily workflows
- Play a pivotal role in elevating knowledge sharing across the organization, contributing to continuous improvement and expertise enhancement
- Act as a dedicated mentor, guiding and supporting team members in their professional growth and project contributions
- Shape the direction of projects by crafting blueprint strategy documents that align precisely with both business and IT requirements
- Provide crucial sales support, leveraging in-depth knowledge to ensure solutions meet client needs and expectations
- Additional Dual Write Integration projects between CRM and ERP and D365 Retail Point of Sale

04/2021 - 04/2023

Hitachi Solutions Canada Ltd., Calgary, Alberta (Canada) Solution Architect, Dynamics 365 Finance & Operations

- Lead D365 Finance & Operations implementation projects, spearheading initiatives as
 Project Lead
- Oversee end-to-end project implementation, covering sales to post-launch support phases
- Create strategic blueprint documents, aligning business and IT goals
- Provide essential support in sales-related activities
- Promote internal knowledge enhancement, fostering organizational improvement
- Serve as a representative for consultants within Hitachi's community council
- Offer assistance across various projects for multiple Hitachi Legal entities

08/2019 - 04/2021

Hitachi Solutions Canada Ltd., Calgary, Alberta (Canada) Senior Finance Consultant, Dynamics 365 Finance & Operations

- Implement Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations as Finance Lead, addressing business requirements in line with product owner needs
- Lead daily stand-ups, tracking project members' progress
- Design customizations in D365 Finance and PowerApps/Microsoft Flow
- Drive Hitachi's internal initiative to develop a business process repository

09/2017 - 08/2019

Hitachi Solutions Germany GmbH, Nürnberg (Germany) Senior Finance Consultant, Dynamics 365 Finance & Operations

- Manage financial ERP roll-outs to European subsidiaries, specializing in retail processes

11/2016 - 09/2017

HSO Enterprise Solutions GmbH, Böblingen (Germany) Finance Consultant. AX 2012

- Develop Functional Design Documents, change requests, queries, and reports
- Support data migration engineers from a financial perspective, ensuring alignment in general ledger and subledgers
- Import data through DIF or Excel Add-In
- Configure advanced bank & cash management settings, such as electronic payment (SEPA) and reconciliation (MT940)
- Establish an asset schedule based on subledger module financial transactions
- Define data interfaces between ERP systems or third-party software
- Possess basic PowerBI knowledge
- Replace outdated ERP solutions like AX4.0 or DATEV
- Participate in pre-sales activities, gathering business requirements
- Assist customers in challenging situations (Customer Service)
- Develop controlling concepts for cost-performance calculations
- Coach junior finance consultants and other employees on finance topics

03/2016 - 11/2016

HSO Enterprise Solutions GmbH, Böblingen (Germany)

Junior Finance Consultant, AX 2012

- Conduct Key-User Training for Dynamics AX 2012 & D365 accounting & controlling processes and AR, AP, GL & FA modules
- Advise and coach customers on optimizing management reporting (static & dynamic reporting)
- Expertise in fixed assets management according to German laws (HGB) and fixed asset module parameterization
- Identify business needs for budgeting & forecasting topics
- Implement single Dynamics AX modules independently

01/2016 - 02/2016

HSO Netherlands, Veenendaal (Netherlands)

Master Class Participant

- Microsoft Dynamics AX training in logistics, project management and finance
- Get in touched with sure step, prince II project methodology
- Presentation- and conversation management trainings

09/2012 - 09/2015

Testo AG, Titisee-Neustadt (Germany)

Working Student

- Bachelor's thesis: "Analysis & Documentation of Appropriate Transfer Pricing Methods"
- Consultancy of Project Managers in implementing controlling systems
- Creation of Key Performance Indicators to evaluate the results of departments
- Controlling measuring system investigations in the field of Lean Management; particularly in Kaizen.

Professional References

Professional references available upon request

Project References

Project references available under https://lopez-coll.com/projects